A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - C-D, 2.2
    - Callan, Albert and Virginia, circa1980s; Sound, 141 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9488)
      Interview. Albert was a Columbia County Republican leader, and Virginia was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Callaway, Bo, circa1980s; Sound, 35 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9489)
      Interview. Callaway was chairman of the President Ford Committee, June 1975-March 1976. Callaway interview ends at 22 minutes, 29 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Warren Weaver until end. Weaver was a reporter for the New York Times.
      Pitch is too high, speed is too fast, and audio crackles for first 22 minutes, 29 seconds, making the interview unintelligible in parts.
    - Camp, John, circa1980s; Sound, 137 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9490)
      Interview. Camp was an AIA-IBEC aide.
    - Campbell, Donald, circa1980s; Sound, 43 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9491)
      Interview. Campbell was a Republican New York State Assemblyman, 1951-1968. He was also Republican Party chairman of Montgomery County.
    - Cannon, Jim, circa1980s; Sound, 282 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9492)
      Interview. Cannon was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller when he was Governor of New York and then Vice President.
    - Canzeri, Joseph, circa1980s; Sound, 154 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9493)
      Interview. Canzeri was a gubernatorial and famiy aide.
    - Carberry, Jim, circa1980s; Sound, 66 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9494)
      Interview. Carberry was a speech writer for Nelson Rockefeller and John Lindsay.
    - Carey, Hugh, circa1980s; Sound, 65 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9495)
      Interview. Carey was a congressman in the U.S. House of Representatives and governor of New York.
    - Carlino, Joseph, circa1980s; Sound, 213 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9496)
      Interview. Carlino was the New York State Assembly Majority Leader.
    - Case, Gene, circa1980s; Sound, 40 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9497)
      Interview. Case was an advertising executive who developed ads for Nelson Rockefeller's successful bid for a third term as governor in 1966.
    - Chilcote, Lee, circa1980s; Sound, 40 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9498)
      Interview. Chilcote was a Dartmouth classmate.
    - Clendinen, Dudley, 1982 April 2; Sound, 21 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15676)
      Interview. Clendinen was a national correspondent and editorial writer for the New York Times, during which he wrote at least one story about Nelson Rockefeller. Tape also contains an interview with Clendinen's wife.
    - Compilation: Barber Conable, John Sears, Oscar Lanford, John Egan, Charles Lanigan, Lois Wilson, circa1980s; Sound, 283 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9586)
      Interview. Conable was a New York State senator and then a member of the U.S. House of Representatives. Conable interview ends at 47 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sears until 72 minutes, 43 seconds. Sears was Ronald Reagan's campaign manager during the 1976 Republican presidential primaries. Tape then contains partial interview with Lanford until 94 minutes, 24 seconds. Lanford was the president of the SUNY Fredonia. Tape then contains partial interview with Egan until 150 minutes, 14 seconds. Egan was commissioner of the Office of General Services. Tape then contains partial interview with Lanigan until 188 minutes, 30 seconds. Lanigan was mayor of Rome, New York, 1959-1962, and later was on Governor Nelson Rockefeller's staff for six connsecutive years in various capacities. Tape then contains partial interview with Wilson until 233 minutes, 32 seconds. Wilson was a gubernatorial aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Conable, Barber, circa1980s; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9499)
      Interview. Conable was a Republican New York State senator and then a member of the U.S. House of Representatives. Conable interview ends at 51 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Oscar Ruebhausen until end. Ruebhausen was a friend and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. Under Governor Rockefeller, Ruebhausen served in a number of capacities, including as chairman of the Special Task Force on Protection from Radioactive Fallout, as Special Adviser on Atomic Energy, and as chairman of a panel on insurance holding companies.
    - Conboy, Brian, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9500)
      Interview. Conboy was campaign manager for U.S. Senator Charles Goodell, Republican from New York.
    - Conway, Edward, circa 1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15682)
      Interview. Conway was a New York State Supreme Court Justice and Republican Party chairman of Albany County. Conway interview ends at 42 minutes, 22 seconds. Tape the contains partial interview with David Rockefeller until end. David Rockefeller was Nelson Rockefeller's brother.
    - Coral, Joy, circa1980s; Sound, 35 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9501)
      Interview. Coral was a Republican worker.
    - Corbett, Raymond, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9502)
      Interview. Corbett was the legislative director of the New York State A.F.L-C.I.O.
    - Corbin, Sol Neil, circa1980s; Sound, 561 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9503)
      Interview. Successively, Corbin was Assistant Counsel to the Governor; Counsel to the Governor; Assistant to the Governor in the Attica riot investigation; and Special Counsel to the Vice President for the Commission on CIA Activities.
    - Corning, Elizabeth, circa1980s; Sound, 45 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9504)
      Interview. Corning was the wife of Erastus Corning, who was the mayor of Albany.
    - Edward N. Costikyan, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9505)
      Interview. Chair of New York County Democratic Committee in 1960s; appointed by Nelson Rockefeller to commission that investigated New York City government in 1970s.
    - Crangle, Joseph, and Rangel, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 131 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9699)
      Interview. Crangle was Erie County Democratic chairman and then New York State Democratic chairman. Crangle interview ends at 93 minutes, 24 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Rangel until end. Rangel was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1967-1970, and a member of the United States House of Representatives, 1971-2017. Governor Nelson Rockefeller endorsed Rangel for his 1968 re-election to the New York State Assembly.
    - Crown, Alfred, 1982 September 16; Sound, 78 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15681)
      Interview. Crown was a film producer who worked in the motion picture divison of the State Department in Latin America during World War 2 showing United States propaganda films to local heads of companies. Outside of that, Crown was president of Moulin Productions and later vice president of international sales for Samuel Goldwyn Productions and R.K.O. Pictures, and he worked for Allied Artists and Aladan Productions. At the time of his death, he was senior vice president in charge of Penthouse Films International Ltd.
    - Cunningham, Evelyn, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9506)
      Interview. Cunningham was a reporter for the Pittsburgh Courier in its Harlem office and special assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. She was appointed director of the Women's Unit within the Governor's Office.
    - Cuomo, Mario, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9507)
      Interview. Cuomo was Secretary of State of New York, 1975-1978, Lieutenant Governor of New York, 1979-1982, and then Governor of New York, 1983-1994. Cuomo interview ends at 68 minutes, 35 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Curcio, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 182 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9508)
      Interview. Curcio was Suffolk County Republican chairman.
    - Curran, Paul, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9509)
      Interview. Curran was a member of the New York State Assembly and chairman of the New York State Commission of Investigation.
    - Curto, Ernest, circa1980s; Sound, 76 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9510)
      Interview. Curto was a Niagara County Republican representative in the New York State Assembly.
    - Danzig, Jerry, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9511)
      Interview. Danzig was Special Assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller for Radio and Television. Danzig interview ends at 71 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with T. Norman Hurd until end. Hurd was Director of State Operations.
    - Deardourff, John, circa1980s; Sound, 127 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9512)
      Interview. Deardourff was a campaign aide.
    - Diamond, Henry, circa1980s; Sound, 176 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9514)
      Interview. Diamond was an environmental lawyer and New York State's first commissioner of environmental conservation. Diamond interivew ends at 55 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Gillies. Gillies was an IBEC aide. Gillies interview ends at 91 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individal until 94 minutes. Tape then continues with interview with Diamond until end.
    - DiCarlo, Dominick, circa 1980s; Sound, 72 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15677)
      Interview. DiCarlo was a Republican New York State Assemblyman, 1965-1981. He was the only Republican in the State Assembly who voted against the Rockfeller drug laws.
    - Dietel, Bill, circa1980s; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9515)
      Interview. Dietel was executive vice president and president of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
    - Dilworth, J. Richardson, circa1980s; Sound, 142 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9516)
      Interview. Richardson was a lawyer and financial adviser to the Rockefeller family and manager of Room 5600.
    - Dominick, D. Clinton, circa1980s; Sound, 74 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9517)
      Interview. Dominick was a member of the New York State Assembly and a New York State senator.
    - Douglass, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 197 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9519)
      Interview. Douglass was first assistant counsel (1964-1965), counsel (1965-1971), and secretary (1971-1972) to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Dudley, George - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 40 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9520)
      Interview. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations headquarters, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany, New York. He also served with Rockefeller at various times in the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; International Basic Economies Corporation; New York State Office of Regional Development; and the Pure Water Authority.
    - Dudley, George - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 282 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9521A)
    - Dudley, George - Part 3, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 285 minutes (Tape AV 9521B)
    - Dudley, George - Part 4, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 141 minutes (Tape AV 9521C)
    - Duggan, Stephen, 1982 September 22?; Sound, 69 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9523)
      Interview. Duggan was a Lincoln School classmate.
    - Dunham, Richard, circa1980s; Sound, 260 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9524)
      Interview. Dunham was deputy budget director and then director of the budget for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Dunham was also deputy director of the White House Domestic Council when Rockefeller was Vice President. Dunham interview ends at 234 minutes, 28 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert MacCrate until end. MacCrate was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Duryea, Perry, circa1980s; Sound, 201 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9525)
      Interview. Duryea was a Republican member of the New York State Assembly.
  - E-G, 2.3
    - Edelman, Peter, circa1980s; Sound, 51 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9526)
      Interview. Edelman was issues director for Arthur Goldberg's New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Edelstein, Julius, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9527)
      Interview. Edelstein was executive assistant to New York City Mayor Robet F. Wagner. Edelstein interview ends at 46 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Egan, John, circa1980s; Sound, 77 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9528)
      Interview. Egan was commissioner of the Office of General Services.
    - Emery, James, circa1980s; Sound, 70 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9529)
      Interview. Emery was Livingston County Sheriff and then a New York State Assemblyman.
    - Engel, David, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9530)
      Interview. Engel was a landscape architect.
    - Erb, Claude, 1982 October 2; Sound, 45 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9531)
      Interview. Erb was a historian.
    - Esposito, Meade, circa1980s; Sound, 183 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9532)
      Interview. Esposito served as Brooklyn Democratic Chair.
    - Fishbein, Peter, circa1980s; Sound, 45 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9533)
      Interview. Fishbein served in Nelson Rockfeller's 1968 Presidential campaign; campaign manager for Arthur Goldberg's unsuccessful 1970 New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Feist, Enid, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9534)
      Interview. Feist was Nelson Rockefeller's deputy campaign director for New York City.
    - Feldman, Justin, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9535)
      Interview. Feldman was a Democratic official.
    - Fish, Marianne, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9536)
      Interview. Fish was Myrtie Tinklepaugh's daughter. Tinklepaugh was a Republican county chairman. Fish interview ends at 74 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Camp until end. Camp was an AIA-IBEC aide.
    - Fisher, Arnold, circa 1980s; Sound, 76 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15679)
      Interview. Fisher was Republican Party chairman of Madison County.
    - Fisher, Harold, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9537)
      Interview. Fisher served as chair of the Metropolitan Transit Authority (MTA) during Governor Nelson Rockefeller's tenure. Fisher interview ends at 89 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Ron Maiorana until end. Maiorana was press secretary and advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Ford, Gerald, circa1980s; Sound, 56 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9538)
      Interview. Ford was the 38th President of the United States.
    - Ford: Panel IIA: The Rockefeller Vice-Presidency, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9539)
      Interview. Panelists include Richard Rosenbaum, Joseph Persico, Peter Wallison, Richard Dunham, and James Cannon. Rosenbaum was appointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to the New York State Supreme Court. Persico was chief speech writer for Rockefeller when he was governor and vice president. Wallison was special assistant to Governor Rockefeller. Dunham was deputy director and then director of the budget for New York. Cannon was assistant to Governor Rockefeller.
    - Forster, Bayard Stuyvesant, circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9540)
      Interview. Forster was New York State commissioner of transportation under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Forster interview ends at 46 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains a phone call with a Mrs. Smith until 61 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Bill Lovelock until end. Lovelock was a detective lieutenant for the NYPD and a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Franciscus, John, 1982 May 5; Sound, 34 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9541)
      Interview. Franciscus worked for IBEC.
    - Free, Lloyd, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9542)
      Interview. Free was a pollster and conducted surveys for Nelson Rockefeller. Free interview ends at 56 minutes, 56 seconds. Tap then contains partial interview with Wilma Rogalin. Rogalin was vice chairman of the New York State Republican Committee and president of its women's federation.
    - French, Eleanor Clark, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9543)
      Interview. French was a cousin of Mary Clark Rockefeller, wife of John French (NAR's roommate at Dartmouth), and a Democratic activist who was the national president of Americans for Democratic Action. French interview ends at 65 minutes, 44 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Friedman, Josh, circa1980s; Sound, 86 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9544)
      Interview. Friedman was a reporter for the New York Post.
    - Friele, Berent - Interview 1, 1982 September 29; Sound, 82 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9545A)
      Interview. Friele was senior vice presdient and director of AIA and an adviser on international relations for Nelson Rockefeller when he was governor of New York and Vice President of the United States.
    - Friele, Berent - Interview 2, 1982 October 7; Sound, 90 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9545B)
    - Galvin, Edward, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9546)
      Interview. Galvin was a bodyguard for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Gardner, John, circa1980s; Sound, 33 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9547)
      Interview. Gardner was a trustee for the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
    - Gart, Murray, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9548)
      Interview. Gart was a journalist and campaign aide. Gart interview starts at 10 minutes, 30 seconds and ends at 78 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape is then blank until 90 minutes, 19 seconds, when there is a partial interview with Bernard Newman until end of tape. Newman was a Republican leader who was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Germond, Jack, circa1980s; Sound, 79 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9549)
      Interview. Germond was a journalist.
    - Gettinger, Jason, circa1980s; Sound, 106 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9550)
      Interview. Gettinger was an attorney.
    - Gilder, George, circa1980s; Sound, 92 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9551)
      Interview. Gilder was a speechwriter for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Gillies, John, circa1980s; Sound, 92 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9552)
      Interview. Gillies was an IBEC and gubernatorial aide.
    - Gilpatric, Roswell, circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9553)
      Interview. Roswell was a Rockefeller Brothers' Special Studies panelist. Roswell interview ends at 39 minutes, 53 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Bennett until end. Bennett was superintendent of the Executive Mansion.
    - Goldberg, David, circa1980s; Sound, 67 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9554)
      Interview. Goldberg was a political consultant.
    - Goldman, Pat, circa1980s; Sound, 63 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9555)
      Interview. Goldman was chair of the Republican Women's Task Force.
    - Goldstone, Harmon, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9556)
      Interview. Goldstone was an accomplished architect who knew Nelson Rockefeller dating back to their years at the Lincoln School in Manhattan.
    - Golub, William, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9557)
      Interview. Golub was an attorney who was Special Assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller for rail and commuter problems. He was also a special consultant to the Moreland Act Commission to draft legislation that created sweeping changes in New York State's liquor laws.
    - Gotbaum, Victor, circa1980s; Sound, 39 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9558)
      Interview. Gotbaum was a New York City labor leader and executive director of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37.
    - Gould, Sam, circa1980s; Sound, 169 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9559)
      Interview. Gould was chancellor of the State University of New York.
    - Graves, Guy, circa1980s; Sound, 141 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9560)
      Interview. Graves was a New York Republican official. Graves interview ends at 125 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Perry Duryea until end. Duryea was a Republican member of the New York State Assembly.
    - Gregg, Hugh and Kay, and Teague, Bert, circa1980s; Sound, 87 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9561)
      Interview. Hugh Gregg was leader of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's Presidential campaign in New Hampshire. Teague was Gregg's protégé and campaign aide.
    - Grimm, Robert, and Russo, Louis, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9562)
      Interview. Grimm was Erie County Republican Chairman. Russo was budget director for Erie County.
    - Grindle, Paul, circa1980s; Sound, 284 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9563)
      Interview. Grindle was a businessman and leader of Henry Cabot Lodge Jr.'s 1964 Presidential campaign.
    - Gwirtzman, Milton, circa1980s; Sound, 4 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9769)
      Interview. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Bobby, and Edward Kennedy. This is the end of the interview contained on AV 9770.
    - Gyory, Bruce, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9564)
      Interview. Gyory was a political consultant.
  - H-K, 2.4
    - Hall, Robert, circa 1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9565)
      Interview. Hall was a newspaper editor and publisher who was appointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to serve on the Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks.
    - Halberg, Herbert B., circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9674)
      Interview. Halberg was Special New York City field coordinator for Governor Nelson Rockefeller's 1970 reelection bid, and former Commissioner of Marine and Aviation in Mayor John Lindsay's administration. Halberg interview ends at 47 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until 70 minutes, 32 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide.
    - Harding, Raymond, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9566)